MIGUEL BRAVO MIGONE

electronics engineer



Santiago, Chile



mbmigone@outlook.com



+56 9 6689 1934



linkedin.com/in/mbravomigone

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

Automation and industrial control. PLC, HMI and SCADA design and programming.

Interpretation and design of electrical, control and P&ID diagrams.
Configuration of industrial equipment and communication networks planning.

Self-guided software development. Web design notions, network systems and servers configuration.

SOFTWARE

- MS Office
- AutoCAD
- Logix Designer
- Unity PRO
- Vijeo Designer
- KepServer OPC
- Visual Studio
- LabVIEW
- MATLAB

EDUCATION

Electronics engineering

Universidad Tecnológica Metropolitana Santiago, Chile. 2014

Certifications & courses

- Certified LabVIEW Associate Developer.
 NI Customer Education
- 6.002x: Circuits and Electronics. MITxedX
- CNC.ETRRx: Introduction to Computer Numerical Control.
- UPEVIPN02x: Object Oriented Programming.
- Mobile Robotics. O2S

PROFILE

Project engineer with +3 years of experience integrating control systems and communication technologies on industrial projects.

Dependable, goal-oriented and problems resolution. Attention to detail and analytics capabilities. Team-player and customer interaction skills through empathy, conscientiousness and transparent communication. Strong work ethics.

EXPERIENCE

2019 – 2021 Working Holiday Canada

International Experience Canada program.

2016 – 2019 ASHIngeniería y Proyectos Project engineer.

Development engineer, systems integration, commissioning and startup of automation, control and industrial communication projects.

- Enel, Bocamina thermal power plant: Control system and data report for continuous emissions monitoring system modernization.
- Barrick, Minera Nevada Company:
 Control system and SCADA development and startup for acid rock drain treatment in reverse osmosis plant.
- Codelco, Gabriela Mistral division:
 Profibus DP network commissioning and certification.
- Puerto Ventanas:
 Harbor crane PLC software upgrade and data acquisition communication interface addition for report generation.
- ASH:
 C# CRUD application for company equipment tracking. MS SQL server database, DevExpress winforms UI and ASP.NET web application on IIS.

2015: Feb – Mar National Instruments NI Internship.

Data acquisition hardware and graphic control interfaces design programming platform study. Applied to the control system design and development for pneumatic industrial process prototype (thesis project).

2013 – 2014 Universidad Tecnológica Metropolitana

Circuits analysis II and Electronics II lectures teaching assistant.